Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Radio Free Europe File, 1951-2004 (Box 11-38)
  - Research materials, 1951-2002
    - Nowak, Jan, 1951-2004 (Box-folder 33: 25-29)
      Includes DVD Alias: Jan Nowak, directed by Jolanta Kessler-Chojecka.
    - Paul VI, Pope, 1996 (Box-folder 33: 30)
    - Poland, 1952-2008
      - Defectors, 1952, 1954 (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
      - Policy review of Voice of Free Poland programming, 1956 December 8 (Box-folder 34: 3)
      - "Post-October Agricultural Policy of Władysław Gomułka,", 1958 (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - "The Situation in Poland, July to November 1958,", 1959 (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - "Poland is Not Yet Lost," by William E. Griffith, circa 1959 (Box-folder 34: 6)
      - Polish press survey, 1962 (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - "Diversion," by Janusz Kolczyński, 1964 (Box-folder 34: 8)
      - Radio Warsaw critique of Zbigniew Brzezinski, 1977 (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - Translations from Radio Warsaw, 1979 (Box-folder 34: 10)
      - "Chronology of Events Related to Broadcasts of Josef Swiatlo on Radio Free Europe and Voice of America," by A. Ross Johnson, 2008 November (Box-folder 34: 11)
    - Press responsibility, 1966 (Box-folder 34: 12)
    - Psychological warfare, 1966 (Box-folder 34: 13)
    - Radio in the American Sector (RIAS or Rundfunk im Amerikanischen Sektor), 1962 (Box-folder 34: 14)
    - Radio Liberty, 1964-1987
      - Mail report, 1964 (Box-folder 34: 15)
      - Audience and content analysis reports, 1965 (Box-folder 34: 16-18)
      - "Looking Forward: Some Attitudes and Aspirations of Soviet People," by Max Ralis, 1965 (Box-folder 34: 19)
      - "Major Trends in Soviet Developments Since Khrushchev,", 1965 (Box-folder 34: 20)
      - Radio Liberty policy manual, 1965 (Box-folder 34: 21)
      - Russian program review, 1965 (Box-folder 35: 1)
      - "Some Patterns of Foreign Radio Listening by Soviet Citizens,", 1966 January 5 (Box-folder 35: 2)
      - "Soviet Central Asia: The Importance of Short-Wave Broadcasting in the Native Languages of Soviet Central Asia,", 1965 (Box-folder 35: 3)
      - Listener report, 1966 May 6 (Box-folder 35: 4)
      - "Agricultural Reform Since Khrushchev: A Progress Report,", 1968 (Box-folder 35: 5)
      - Annual report, 1973 (Box-folder 35: 6)
      - Radio Liberty Research Bulletin, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 35: 7-14)
      - RFE/RL temporary visitor's pass, 1990 December 2 (Box-folder 35: 15)
      - Printed matter, 1960s (Box-folder 35: 16)
    - Radio Study Group, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 35: 17-19)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 20)
    - Romania, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 35: 21-23)
    - Soviet Union, 1964-1986 (Box-folder 36: 1-4)
    - Stalin, Joseph, 1953, 1962 (Box-folder 36: 5-6)
    - Trifa, Valerian D., 1979-1981 (Box-folder 36: 7-10)
      Relates to complaints filed against RFE for broadcasting an interview with Trifa, a former member of the Iron Guard.
    - United States International Communication Agency, 1977-1979, 1997 (Box-folder 36: 11-15)
    - Voice of America, 1984 (Box-folder 36: 16)
    - Walter, Ralph, 2002 (Box-folder 36: 17)
    - Weems, Constance Dulles, 1980 (Box-folder 36: 18)
  - Clippings, 1953-1971 (Box-folder 36: 19-24)
  - Printed matter, 1950s-1992
    - Radio Free Europe promotional brochures and pamphlets, 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 37: 1-4)
    - The Radio Free Europe Story, 1958 June (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - Nikolaev, S. and M. Lepekhin, 1972 (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - Atlas, Moscow, 1989 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Atlas, 1992 September (Box-folder 38: 2)
- The Plot to Kill the Pope File, 1972-2000 (Box 39-58)
  Contains correspondence, clippings, court documents, reports, notes, transcripts, film scripts, speeches and writings, and a photograph.
  Arranged in subseries by physical form, then alphabetically and thereunder chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1982-1999
    - Unidentified, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Routine, 1982-1990
      - A (Box-folder 39: 2)
      - B (Box-folder 39: 3)
      - C (Box-folder 39: 4)
      - D (Box-folder 39: 5)
      - E (Box-folder 39: 6)
      - F (Box-folder 39: 7)
      - G (Box-folder 39: 8)
      - H (Box-folder 39: 9)
      - K-L (Box-folder 39: 10)
      - M (Box-folder 39: 11)
      - N (Box-folder 39: 12)
      - O-P (Box-folder 39: 13)
      - R-S (Box-folder 39: 14)
      - T (Box-folder 39: 15)
      - U (Box-folder 39: 16)
      - W-Y (Box-folder 39: 17)
    - Ağca, Adnan, circa 1982 (Box-folder 39: 18)
    - Alatas, Kazım, 1983 (Box-folder 39: 19)
    - Alexiev, Alex, 1991 (Box-folder 39: 20)
    - Bartley, Robert, 1983 (Box-folder 39: 21)
    - Bojkov, Pasko, 1988 (Box-folder 39: 22)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1984 (Box-folder 39: 23)
    - Cambel, Leyla, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 39: 24)
    - Campany, Richard, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 39: 25)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 39: 26)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 39: 27)
    - Corabatır, Metin, 1985 (Box-folder 39: 28)
    - Croom, David, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 39: 29-32)
    - DuCharme, Ellen, 1988 (Box-folder 39: 33)
    - Ehrenfeld, Rachel, 1987 (Box-folder 39: 34)
    - Elekdağ, Sükrü, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 39: 35)
    - Eralp, Yalım, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - Friedman, Todd, 1998 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Fuller, Graham, 1988 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - Gaffney, Devon, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Gönen, Erbay, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - Gönensay, Aylin, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Gönlübol, Mehmet, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - Gounev, Georgy, 1990 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - Green, Harlan, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - Gunter, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Hawkins, Paula, 1984 (Box-folder 40: 11)
    - Hic, Mükerrem, 1981-2009 (Box-folder 40: 12-13)
    - Hoover Institution, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 14)
    - Jenkins, Brian, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 15)
    - Kalaycıoğlu, Ersin, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 16)
    - Karaosmanoğlu, Ali L., 1986 (Box-folder 40: 17)
    - Karpat, Kemal, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 18)
    - Kevenk, Kerim, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 40: 19)
    - Kılıc, Altemur, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 20)
    - Köni, Hasan, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 21)
    - Kurbegovic, Muharem, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 22)
      Also known as the "Alphabet Bomber."
    - Kuzio, Taras, 1984 (Box-folder 40: 23)
    - Landau, Jacob, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 24)
    - Lowry, Heath, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 40: 25)
    - Magnarella, Paul, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 26)
    - McGowan, Bruce, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 27)
    - McKenzie, Kenneth, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 40: 28)
    - The New York Times, 1983 (Box-folder 40: 29)
    - Öke, Mim Kemal, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 30)
    - Okyar, Osman, 1988 (Box-folder 40: 31)
    - Onulduran, Ersin, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 40: 32)
    - Özer, Ayhan, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 40: 33)
    - Paksoy, Hasan, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 40: 34)
    - Rau, William, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 40: 35)
    - Rimbach, Ralph, 1999 (Box-folder 40: 36)
    - Tashan, Seyfi, 1985 (Box-folder 40: 37)
    - Tercüman, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 38)
    - Tolun, Yavus, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 40: 39)
    - Tülümen, Turgut, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 40)
    - Tuncel, Erhan, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 41)
    - U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1984 (Box-folder 40: 42)
    - Vassilev, Rossen, 1988 (Box-folder 40: 43)
    - The Washington Post, 1985 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Weigel, George, 1998 (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - Weisbrode, Kenneth, 1999 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - Wohlstetter, Albert, 1985 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - Wolfe, Dana, 1987 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - Wriggins, Howard, 1983 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - Yalcın, Aydın, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 41: 7-8)
    - Zentürk, Ardan, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 41: 9-10)
  - Research materials, 1972-2000
    Unless otherwise indicated, consists of clippings, printed matter, and reports. In alphabetical order by subject, thereunder chronologically.
    - General, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 41: 11-22)
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 42: 1-12)
    - General, 1985-1988, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 43: 1-11)
    - Ağca, Mehmet Ali, 1981-1993
      - Notes by Henze, 1981 (Box-folder 43: 12)
      - Identification documents, 1981 (Box-folder 43: 13)
        Includes report on Ağca's education by Mükerrem Hic.
      - Court documents, 1981, 1984 (Box-folder 44: 1-4)
      - Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 44: 5-15)
      - Clippings, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 45: 1-21)
    - Bitov, Oleg, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Bulgaria, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 46: 2-14)
      Clippings related primarily to the "Bulgarian connection." Includes notes by Henze in Gregg shorthand.
    - Celenk, Bekir, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 46: 15-18)
      Includes Turkish court documents.
    - Disinformation, 1972-1988 (Box-folder 47: 1-19)
      Includes articles by and about Iona Andronov.
      - Palestinian Liberation Organization, 1982-1983
        - Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 48: 12-13)
        - Documents captured by Israeli Defense Forces in Lebanon, photocopies, 1982 June
          - "The Nature of the Activities of the Palestinian Terrorists in South Lebanon and their Ties with Eastern Bloc Countries" (Box-folder 48: 14)
          - "Palestinian Terrorists Training in the Soviet Union: Report to Arafat by Head of Delegation" (Box-folder 48: 15)
          - "Protocol of Talks between PLO and Soviet Delegations in Moscow" (Box-folder 48: 16)
          - "Saudi Arabian Arms Supplies to the Palestinian Terrorists" (Box-folder 48: 17)
    - Drugs, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Italy, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 48: 2)
    - John Paul II, Pope, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 48: 3-5)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1980-1984 (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Mumcu, Uğur, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 48: 7-9)
    - Nâzım Hikmet, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 48: 10-11)
    - Poland, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 48: 18-19)
    - Soviet Union, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 48: 20)
    - Sterling, Claire, 1982 (Box-folder 48: 21)
    - Terrorism, 1970-1994
      - General, 1970-1988 (Box-folder 49: 1-13)
      - Armenia, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 49: 14-16)
      - Ireland, 1982 (Box-folder 49: 17)
      - Italy, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 50: 1-6)
      - Kurdistan, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 50: 7-8)
      - Latin America, 1980 (Box-folder 50: 9)
      - North America, 1982 (Box-folder 50: 10)
      - Soviet Union, 1981 (Box-folder 50: 11)
      - Turkey, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 50: 12-22)
      - Turkey, 1985-1994 (Box-folder 51: 1-11)
  - Draft and publication file, 1979-1991
    - Notes, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 52: 1)
      Relates primarily to Abdi Ipekçi, Mehmet Ali Ağca and Claire Sterling.
    - Book proposal, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Typescript, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 3-5)
    - Chapter three, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 6)
    - Photographs, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 7-11)
    - Revisions, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Publication clearances from the Central Intelligence Agency and the National Security Council, 1983, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 2-3)
    - Published copies, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 4)
    - Rights and permissions, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - Postscript, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 6)
    - Polish edition rights, 1991 (Box-folder 53: 7)
    - Zbigniew Brzezinski's introduction to the Polish edition, 1991 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Promotional file, 1981-1991
    - Clippings and transcripts from television appearances, 1981-1995 (Box-folder 54: 1-12)
    - Interviews, 1982-1990
      - CNN, 1982 (Box-folder 55: 1)
        Includes photograph.
      - Yeni Forum, 1983 (Box-folder 55: 2)
      - Voice of America, 1986 (Box-folder 55: 3)
      - Bulgarian press, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 55: 4)
      - Polish press, 1990 (Box-folder 55: 5)
    - Reviews, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 55: 6-11)
  - Film adaptation, 1984-1991
    - Correspondence, 1984-1991
      - Bale International Film Company, 1984 (Box-folder 56: 1)
      - Watermill Productions, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 56: 2)
    - Screenplays, circa 1987
      - "Crime of the Century," by George Englund (Box-folder 56: 3)
      - "Plot to Kill the Polish Pope," by T.R. Bowen (Box-folder 56: 4-5)
    - Promotional materials, 1988 (Box-folder 56: 6)
      For the film The Most Dangerous Man in the World, based on the screenplay by T.R. Bowen.
  - Speeches and writings, 1981-1987
    - "Goal: Destabilization--Soviet Agitational Propaganda, Instability and Terrorism in NATO South," paper for the European American Institute for Security Research Workshop, 1981 August (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - "Mehmet Ali Ağca: Whose Agent?," report, 1981 September (Box-folder 57: 2)
    - "From Malatya to Rome: The Evolution of an Assassin," report prepared for Reader's Digest, 1981 December (Box-folder 57: 3)
    - "Terrorism in Turkey--Russians as Peace-Loving Neighbors,", 1982 June (Box-folder 57: 4)
    - "International Terrorism: The Russian Background and the Soviet Linkage," paper for the Canadian Political Science Association, 1982 June 9 (Box-folder 57: 5)
    - "Coping with Terrorism: What Do We Know? What Can Be Done?," paper for the Conference of the Political and Social Studies Foundation (SISAV), Istanbul, 1982 October 3-6 (Box-folder 57: 6)
    - "Will Andropov Play the Albanian Card?,", 1982 December 22 (Box-folder 57: 7)
    - "Washington Wonders if Papal Plot Is Soviet Watergate,", 1982 December 23 (Box-folder 57: 8)
    - "Terrorismus und das Attentat auf den Papst,", 1983 (Box-folder 57: 9)
    - "Uğur Mumcu: Caveat Emptor,", 1983 (Box-folder 57: 10)
    - "A Turkish Twist in Plot to Kill Pope,", 1983 January 6 (Box-folder 57: 11)
    - "The Bulgarian Connection,", 1983 February (Box-folder 57: 12)
    - "Washington and the Papal Plot,", 1983 March 2 (Box-folder 57: 13)
    - "Probe of Papal Plot Uncovers Network of International Subversion,", 1983 March 17 (Box-folder 57: 14)
    - "Turkey Retraces Assassin's Murky Trail,", 1983 March 18 (Box-folder 57: 15)
    - "Soviet Press turns Shrill over Alleged Plot against Pope,", 1983 March 21 (Box-folder 57: 16)
    - "Quest for an Assassin,", 1983 May (Box-folder 57: 17)
    - "Facing Reality: Terrorism and the Plot Against the Pope," paper for the European Conference for Human Rights and Self-Determination, 1983 May 9-10 (Box-folder 57: 18)
    - "Origins of the Plot to Kill the Pope,", 1983 Autumn (Box-folder 57: 19)
    - "Misinformation and Disinformation: The Plot to Kill the Pope,", 1983 Autumn (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - "Italy Gets Ready to Release Findings of Inquiry into Attack on Pope,", 1984 January 25 (Box-folder 58: 2)
    - "Washington Reacts to the 'Bulgarian Connection,'", 1984 June 13 (Box-folder 58: 3)
    - "Increments in 'Plot' Against Pope Are Only the Tip of the Iceberg,", 1984 October 30 (Box-folder 58: 4)
    - "Terrorist Rehabilitation in Turkey: The Political Challenge,", 1985 January (Box-folder 58: 5-6)
    - "Like Moscow, Bulgaria Contends with Rising Muslim Population,", 1985 February 22 (Box-folder 58: 7)
    - "Turkish Report Sheds Light on Bulgarian Link to Pope's Assailant,", 1985 March 6 (Box-folder 58: 8)
    - "Coping with Terrorism,", 1985 (Box-folder 58: 9)
    - "Conspiring to Kill the Pope,", 1985 May (Box-folder 58: 10)
    - "Return to Turkey of Defendant in Pope Trial May Add Twist to Case,", 1985 July 15 (Box-folder 58: 11)
    - "Italian Judges in Papal Plot Trial Keep Working, Even During Recess,", 1985 September 5 (Box-folder 58: 12)
    - "Turkey Gives Temporary Haven to Fleeing Iranians on Way to U.S.,", 1985 September 19 (Box-folder 58: 13)
    - "Turkish Government Tackles Problem of Kurdish Insurgency,", 1985 October 30 (Box-folder 58: 14)
    - "Plot to Kill the Pope: A Balance Sheet in the Wake of the Rome Trial,", 1986 June (Box-folder 58: 15)
    - "Turkey, Greece and the U.S. National Interest,", 1987 January (Box-folder 58: 16)
    - "Turkey: Toward the 21st Century,", 1992 (Box-folder 58: 17)
    - "What Ataturk Did Not Do,", 1998 (Box-folder 58: 18)
- Horn of Africa File, 1959-2009 (Box 59-143)
  Contains correspondence, diaries, clippings, speeches and writings, conference files, reports, itineraries, printed matter, maps, and photographs.
  - Correspondence, 1969-2008
    As is customary with Ethiopian names, alphabetical order is by the first name.
    - A-J, 1969-2008 (Box-folder 59: 1-9)
    - K-Z, 1969-2008 (Box-folder 60: 1-14)
    - Unidentified, 1974-1999 (Box-folder 60: 15)
    - Ababa Gessesse, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 60: 16)
    - Adair, E. Ross (Edwin Ross) and Marian, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 60: 17)
    - Addis Ababa University Press (Taddesse Tamrat), 1999 (Box-folder 60: 18)
    - Addis Ababa American Community School (Floyd Travis), 1969-1972 (Box-folder 60: 19)
    - Africa Contemporary Record (Miriam Holmes), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 60: 20)
    - Africa World Press, 1992 (Box-folder 60: 21)
    - Alemayehu Ameneshawa, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 60: 22)
    - Amhara Development Association, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 60: 23)
    - Asfa-Wossen Asserate, 2004 (Box-folder 60: 24-25)
    - Balicka-Witakowska, Ewa, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Bell, Stephen, 2001 (Box-folder 61: 2)
    - Berhane Deressa, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 61: 3)
    - Berhane Gebre Christos, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 61: 4)
    - Berhanu Balcha, 2001-2006 (Box-folder 61: 5)
    - Berhanu Kebede, 2008 (Box-folder 61: 6)
    - Blaustein, Albert P., 1978 (Box-folder 61: 7)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 61: 8)
    - Burns, John (Public Affairs Officer at the U.S. Embassy Addis Ababa), 1987-1989 (Box-folder 61: 9-10)
    - C. Hurst and Company, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 61: 11)
    - Campbell, Ian, 2007 (Box-folder 61: 12)
    - CARE International in Ethiopia (Robin Needham), 1992 (Box-folder 61: 13)
      Includes "Chronology of Security Incidents Affecting CARE personnel in Ethiopia."
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 61: 14-15)
      Includes Carter's correspondence with Mengistu Haile-Mariam and Cyrus Vance.
    - Chojnacki, Stanisław, 1972-2001 (Box-folder 61: 16-21)
    - Chojnacki, Stanisław, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 62: 1-8)
    - Clapham, Christopher, 1984-2008 (Box-folder 63: 1-8)
    - Cohen, John M., 1982-1989 (Box-folder 63: 9-10)
    - Davis, Nadene and Ira, 1993 (Box-folder 63: 11)
    - Dawit Wolde Giorgis, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 63: 12)
    - Diamond, Larry Jay, 2001 (Box-folder 63: 13)
    - Dover Publications, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 63: 14)
    - Elias Wondimu, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 63: 15)
    - Eskinder Nega, 1988 (Box-folder 63: 16)
    - Ethiopia Observer, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 63: 17)
    - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 63: 18)
    - Frantz, Ken, 2006 (Box-folder 63: 19)
    - Gabre-Tinsaye Adhana, 1977 (Box-folder 63: 20)
    - Gitelson, Susan, 1978 (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - Gore, Albert, 1990 (Box-folder 64: 2)
    - Grierson, Roderick, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 64: 3)
    - Henze, Martha, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 64: 4-5)
    - Hickey, Tony, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 64: 6)
    - Hillman, Jesse C., 1992-1993 (Box-folder 64: 7)
    - Hodes, Richard, 1987 (Box-folder 64: 8-9)
    - Hoover Institution (Dennis Bark), 1986 (Box-folder 64: 10-11)
    - Houdek, Robert, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 64: 12)
    - Huddleston, Vicki J., 2006 (Box-folder 64: 13)
    - Isaac, Ephraim, 1991 (Box-folder 64: 14)
    - Isaias Afwerki, 1991 (Box-folder 64: 15)
    - Iskinder Desta, 1974 (Box-folder 64: 16)
    - Journal of Democracy, 1998 (Box-folder 64: 17)
    - Juel-Jensen, Bent, 1979 (Box-folder 64: 18)
    - Kane, Thomas, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 64: 19-20)
      Includes a copy of Kane's diary from 1977-1978.
    - Kane, Thomas, 1988-2000 (Box-folder 65: 1-3)
    - Kendie, Daniel, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 65: 4)
    - Kifle Wodajo, 1993 (Box-folder 65: 5)
    - Korn, David and Roberta, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 65: 6)
    - Krylov, A.B., 1990-1991 (Box-folder 65: 7)
    - Leh, Robert G., 1978 (Box-folder 65: 8)
    - Levine, Donald Nathan, 2000-2009 (Box-folder 65: 9-12)
    - Marx, Annagret, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
    - Mason, Louise, 1969 (Box-folder 66: 3)
    - Meles Zenawi, 1989-2005 (Box-folder 66: 4-6)
    - Mersha Aleheghe, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 66: 7)
    - Mesfin Wolde-Mariam, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 8)
    - Mizane Christos Yohannes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 66: 9)
    - National Endowment for Democracy (Carl Gershman), 1991 (Box-folder 66: 10)
    - Nebiyeloul family, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 66: 11)
    - Nixon, G. Cameron, 1978 (Box-folder 66: 12)
    - Nixon, Lessie Sinclair, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 66: 13-14)
    - Pankhurst, Richard, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 66: 15-16)
      See also: Box 4.
    - Parmalee, Jennifer, 1993 (Box-folder 66: 17)
    - Patman, Robert G., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 66: 18)
    - Plant, Ruth, 1979 (Box-folder 66: 19)
    - Polhemus, James, 2006 (Box-folder 66: 20)
    - Reja, Yusuf, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 66: 21)
    - Ricci, Lanfranco, 1990 (Box-folder 66: 22)
    - Schaefer, Charles, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 66: 23)
    - Seaver, Brenda, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 66: 24)
    - Sergew Hable Selassie, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 25)
    - Seyoum Berhe, 2005 (Box-folder 66: 26)
    - Seyoum Wolde, 1989 (Box-folder 66: 27)
    - Shiferaw Bekele, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 67: 1)
    - Shinn, David and Judy, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 67: 2)
    - Sisay Asefa, 2001, 2006 (Box-folder 67: 3-4)
    - Sorenson, Martha, 1991 (Box-folder 67: 5)
      Includes photograph of Princess Ruth Desta.
    - Spencer, John H., 1986-1988 (Box-folder 67: 6)
    - Stornoway Productions, 1988 (Box-folder 67: 7)
    - Stren, Richard, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 8)
    - Tabotu Woldemichael, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 67: 9)
    - Tadesse Tamrat, 1985-1999 (Box-folder 67: 10)
    - Tafari Wassen, 1992 (Box-folder 67: 11)
    - Tafari Wossen, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 67: 12)
    - Taffara Deguefe, 1989-2001 (Box-folder 67: 13-14)
    - Tucker, Stevens P., 1999 (Box-folder 67: 15)
    - Ullendorf, Edward, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 67: 16)
    - United States Embassy in Ethiopia (Roberta Korn, Owen Roberts, Janet Roberts, Richard C. Matheron, Princeton Lyman), 1971-1983 (Box-folder 67: 17)
    - United States Institute of Peace, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 67: 18)
    - Voice of America, 1988 (Box-folder 67: 19)
      Letters to VOA from listeners in Ethiopia.
    - Warden, Gail, 1999 (Box-folder 67: 20)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 67: 21)
      Includes grant application.
    - Westview Press, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 67: 22)
    - White, Tim, 2001-2007 (Box-folder 67: 23)
    - Wilson Quarterly, 1984 (Box-folder 67: 24)
    - Witten, Wray, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 67: 25)
  - Diaries, 1970-2006
    - Undated (Box-folder 68: 1-2)
    - 1970 December-1971 January (Box-folder 68: 3)
      Simen Mountains, Ethiopia. Includes negatives.
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 68: 4)
      Entries from multiple visits to Lake Zway, Ethiopia.
    - 1977 September 5-17 (Box-folder 68: 5)
      From his time on the National Security Council, relates mainly to a visit to Mogadishu, Somalia.
    - 1978 February 16-21 (Box-folder 68: 6)
      Addis Ababa.
    - 1980 December 27-1981 January 31 (Box-folder 68: 7)
      Ethiopia, Kenya and Israel. Includes photographs of a parade in Addis Ababa.
    - 1984 March 13-15 (Box-folder 68: 8)
      Ethiopia.
    - 1984 November-December (Box-folder 68: 9)
    - 1987 March-April (Box-folder 68: 10)
    - 1988 March (Box-folder 68: 11)
      Hararghe, Ethiopia.
    - 1989 February (Box-folder 68: 12)
    - 1990 September 23-October 2 (Box-folder 68: 13)
      Describes a visit to Nieborow, Poland for the second International Ethiopian Art Conference.
    - 1990 November 26-December 12 (Box-folder 68: 14)
    - 1991 June (Box-folder 68: 15)
    - 1993 March-May (Box-folder 69: 1)
      Constitutional Commission and Eritrean Referendum.
    - 1993 December (Box-folder 69: 2)
    - 1995 January-February (Box-folder 69: 3)
    - 1997 March-April (Box-folder 69: 4)
    - 1998 February (Box-folder 69: 5)